<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<am:entry xmlns:am="http://arcomage.netvor.sk">
<am:content xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<h2>Welcome to MArcomage</h2>

<hr/>

<p style="text-align: center">Authors (in alphabetical order): <a href="http://helppage.3dfx.sk/fendek/">Mojmír Fendek</a> (Mojko) and <a href="mailto:theultramage@gmail.com">Viktor Štujber</a> (theultramage)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.w3.org/">W3C</a> standards compatible browser with enabled JavaScript and Cookies is recommended for full experience. We recommend <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/?from=getfirefox">Firefox</a> or <a href="http://www.google.com/chrome/">Chrome</a> for basic users and <a href="http://www.opera.com/">Opera</a> for advanced users.</p>

<h3>About the game</h3>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcomage">Arcomage</a> is a fantasy turn-based card game. This card game simulates an epic battle between two empires including features such as constructing new buildings, training troops and decimating the enemy empire with standard attacks or sneaky tactics such as intrigue or spells. MArcomage (Multiplayer Arcomage) is an online card game (for two human players) inspired by original Arcomage. There are similarities in gameplay, but there are differences in cards, game rules or victory conditions.</p>

<h4>Game features</h4>

<ul>
	<li>Deck building - choose 45 unique cards to construct your own deck</li>
	<li>Over 600 cards to choose from</li>
	<li>Advanced deck building interface allows you to use multiple filters to find the desired cards quickly</li>
	<li>Experience based leveling system allows you to unlock extra features</li>
	<li>Discuss anything Arcomage related on our forum</li>
	<li>Private messages</li>
	<li>In game chat</li>
	<li>Configure the layout to your best liking by selecting skins, uploading your avatar and other layout options such as background image or card layout</li>
	<li>Advanced game mechanics, not available in original Arcomage
		<ul>
			<li>Multiple victory types allows you to apply different strategies</li>
			<li>New game mechanics such as keywords, tokens, card summoning and many more</li>
			<li>Different game modes allows you to play different variations of the game</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
	<li>Design your own cards and submit them for implementation</li>
</ul>

<p>In order to play, the player must construct his own deck (there are three preconstructed decks available) and challenge other players. The battle begins as soon as the other side accepts. It is possible to chat with your opponent in game.</p>

<p>Advantage of this game is its turn based play style. It allows players to play as often as they like. For example you can play few turns a day, but if you want, you can play all the time, provided you find an opponent willing to play all day as well.</p>

<h4>Links</h4>
<ul>
	<li>The project's location: <a href="http://arcomage.netvor.sk/">http://arcomage.netvor.sk/</a>.</li>
	<li>The official #arcomage channel: <a href="irc://irc.freenode.org/arcomage">irc.freenode.org</a>. Everybody's invited!</li>
	<li>A powerful wiki and bug tracking system at <a href="https://netvor.sk/trac/arcomage">https://netvor.sk/trac/arcomage</a>.</li>
	<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/uc?id=0BydnMBGrM4NWNmY3ZDE1MjItMzMxYS00YzMxLWI5MjQtMTQyM2VkOGU3ODU4&amp;export=download&amp;authkey=CNbY7foB&amp;hl=en">Original Arcomage</a> - standalone version</li>
	<li><a href="http://www.gatewayheaven.com/projects/arcomage/">Arcomage Tribute</a> - a fan-made open source project (single player only)</li>
</ul>

<h4>MArcomage preview images</h4>

<p><a href="img/screen_deck_section.png"><img src="img/screen_deck_section_s.png" alt="deck editor"/></a></p>
<p><a href="img/screen_game_section.png"><img src="img/screen_game_section_s.png" alt="card battle"/></a></p>

</am:content>
</am:entry>
