<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<am:entry xmlns:am="http://arcomage.netvor.sk">
<am:content xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<h4>Overview</h4>
<p>
<acronym title="Multiplayer Arcomage">MArcomage</acronym> is an online card game inspired by the classic <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcomage">Arcomage</a> minigame.
This card game simulates an epic battle between two empires including features such as constructing new buildings, training troops and decimating the enemy empire with standard attacks or sneaky tactics such as intrigue or spells.
MArcomage greatly expands on the original game's ideas while preserving its apperance and core gameplay mechanics.
</p>
<p>
In order to play, the player must construct his own deck (there are three preconstructed decks available) and challenge other players.
The battle begins as soon as the other side accepts.
It is possible to chat with your opponent in game.
</p>
<p>
An advantage of this game is its turn based play style.
It allows players to play as often as they like.
For example you can play few turns a day, but if you want, you can play all the time, provided you find an opponent willing to play all day as well.
</p>

<h4>Features</h4>
<ul>
	<li><b>deck building</b> - construct 45-card decks out of a pool of 600+ unique cards, using complex search filters</li>
	<li><b>match-making</b> - host a game and wait for someone to join, challenge specific players, or practice against the game AI</li>
	<li><b>turn-based</b> - play at your own pace, as slow as you like or as fast as your opponent can keep up</li>
	<li><b>interaction</b> - talk to other players via forums, private messaging or in-game chat</li>
	<li><b>ranking</b> - player ladder, experience-based leveling, unlockable extra features, achievements, gameplay statistics</li>
	<li><b>personalization</b> - avatar images, multiple color and background schemes, various card and game layout options</li>
	<li><b>enhanced gameplay</b>, not available in original Arcomage
		<ul>
			<li>new game mechanics (keywords, tokens, card summoning and many more)</li>
			<li>special game modes (friendly play, hidden cards, long mode)</li>
			<li>multiple victory types (destruction, tower building, resource accumulation, surrender)</li>
			<li>game history browser and replay database, turn outcome preview, in-game notepad</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
</ul>

<h4>Screenshots</h4>
<p>
	<a style="text-decoration:none" href="img/screen_game_section.jpg"><img src="img/screen_game_section_s.jpg" width="328px" height="200px" title="card battle" alt="card battle"/></a>
	<a style="text-decoration:none" href="img/screen_deck_section.jpg"><img src="img/screen_deck_section_s.jpg" width="328px" height="200px" title="deck editor" alt="deck editor"/></a>
</p>

<h4>Links</h4>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://arcomage.netvor.sk/">http://arcomage.netvor.sk/</a> - official website (you are here).</li>
	<li><a href="irc://irc.freenode.org/arcomage">irc://irc.freenode.org/#arcomage</a> - irc channel, everybody's invited!</li>
	<li><a href="https://netvor.sk/trac/arcomage">https://netvor.sk/trac/arcomage</a> - wiki and bug tracking system.</li>
	<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/uc?id=0BydnMBGrM4NWNmY3ZDE1MjItMzMxYS00YzMxLWI5MjQtMTQyM2VkOGU3ODU4&amp;export=download&amp;authkey=CNbY7foB&amp;hl=en">Original Arcomage</a> - standalone version.</li>
	<li><a href="http://www.gatewayheaven.com/projects/arcomage/">Arcomage Tribute</a> - a fan-made open source project (single player only).</li>
</ul>

<h4>Contact</h4>
<ul>
	<li>Mojmír Fendek - <a href="?location=Players_details&amp;Profile=Mojko">Mojko</a> - <a href="mailto:mfendek@gmail.com">mfendek@gmail.com</a></li>
	<li>Viktor Štujber - <a href="?location=Players_details&amp;Profile=theultramage">theultramage</a> - <a href="mailto:theultramage@gmail.com">theultramage@gmail.com</a></li>
</ul>

</am:content>
</am:entry>
