<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xsl:stylesheet [ <!ENTITY rarr "&#8594;"> ]>
<am:entry xmlns:am="http://arcomage.netvor.sk">
<am:content xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<h2>Game manual</h2>
<hr />

<p>
Arcomage is a fantasy turn-based card game.
This card game simulates an epic battle between two empires including features such as constructing new buildings, training troops and decimating the enemy empire with standard attacks or sneaky tactics such as intigue or spells.
MArcomage is its online version for two human players.
</p>

<h4>Overview</h4>
<p>
<a style="float: right;" href="img/screen_start_game.png"><img src="img/screen_start_game_s.png" alt="start game screen"/></a>
The game consists of rounds. Round consists of turns. In most cases one round consists of only one turn, but some cards allow player to make additional turns in the same round. In one turn a player can play one card. Then the next turn follows. After end of player's round it's his opponent's round, where he gets to play card(s).
This way the players play the game - always one playing cards and the other one waiting for the next round where he can play cards.
The cards themselves modify some attributes of the game (such as tower and wall height, resources ...).
The game is very simple and easy to operate. There is much information on the game screen, we will now describe some basic information, in the picture to the right. In the upper left of the screen, your login name is written. In the upper part you can see the navigation bar, which is used to travel between sections. Right below the navigation bar you can see the round indicator, that keeps you informed in which round the game currently is. In the center-left part there is a game list manager. You can use it to jump to another game or you can traverse trough games, in which your turn is, via "Next game" button. In the center of the screen you can see card history. There are no cards there yet, but later it will hold the card(s) recently played by you and your opponent. Above card history is the notice which informs you which player's turn currently is. When waiting for opponent's turn, you need to refresh the game with our refresh button. Furthermore if opponent's name (above the tower and wall information) is colored green it means that he is currently on-line.
</p>

<p>For practice you can <a href="http://www.x-factor.tym.sk/Arcomage/Arcomage.rar">download</a> and play single player Arcomage to learn the basics.</p>

<h4>Game attributes: Resources, facilities, resource production, tower and wall</h4>
<p>
<a style="float: right;" href="img/screen_resources.png"><img src="img/screen_resources_s.png" alt="resources"/></a>
Every player has three types of resources: Bricks, Gems and Recruits, and three types of resource production facilities: Quarry, Magic and Dungeon (generating resources in the corresponding order).
Bricks are the basic building material, used mostly for constructing buildings.
Magic powered soul gems (shortly gems) represent the magical power at your disposal.
And finally, recruits represent your living or fighting power (ammount of creatures, soldiers and weapons).
At the end of round, for each facility of certain type, one resource of the corresponding type is added to the active player's stock.
Example: If Quarry = 3, at the end of round, three Bricks will be added to the stock.
The number of facilities of any kind cannot drop below one, and the ammount of a resource of a certain type cannot be lower than zero. In the picture you can see where resources and facilities info is displayed. Your resources and facilities are to the left and opponent's  are to the right. Every player has his/her own tower and wall, each having a height. Tower height can be at most 100, wall has height limit 150. In the case of a standard enemy attack, the attack will first lower the wall. Only after the wall height is zero and some attack power still remains will the tower be lowered. Example: Enemy attacks with an attack power of 25, wall height is 10, tower height is 20. After the attack, the wall height will be zero and the tower height will be 5. There are some cards that do damage to the tower directly, bypassing the wall. Tower and wall information are located in the bottom-left part (yours) and bottom-right (opponent's). Moreover, if some of these game attributes were changed due to effect of some card, it will be indicated by a small number next to the effected attribute. Cost of a played card and normal production are not displayed in the changes. Zero production is displayed as a loss of resources.
</p>

<h4>Victory types</h4>			
<p>
The goal of the game is to defeat your opponent by reaching one or more victory conditions.
The following outcomes are possible:
</p>
<ul>
<li>
<b>tower destruction</b><br/>
Raze the enemy tower to the ground to win - meaning, lower the enemy tower to zero height. Usually achieved by green cards and standard attacks.
</li>
<li>
<b>tower building</b><br/>
Build up your tower to height 100 to win. Usually achieved by delaying enemy attacks while building your tower.
</li>
<li>
<b>resource accumulation</b><br/>
Accumulate 400 of resources (total sum) to win. Beware of cards that cripple your stock.
</li>
<li>
<b>timeout</b><br/>
Each game is limited to 250 rounds. Afterwards, both players' states are compared (in the order: tower, wall, no. of facilities, sum of resources). Whoever has more (in that order), wins. Otherwise the game is declared a draw.
</li>
</ul>
<p>
Special rules apply in the case where both players achieve a victory condition simultaneously.
<br/>
If the victory type for both is the same, the result is, logically, a draw.
<br/>
If the victory types are different, the following rule is used to determine the winner:
Destruction victory > Tower bulding victory > Resource victory > Timeout victory.
</p>
<p>After the game is finished and a player leaves the game, his opponent is informed about this with "player has left the game" message in the chat window.</p>

<h4>Special game end types</h4>

<p>Game can be ended in different way when certain conditions are met.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<b>surrender</b><br/>
Each player can use the "Surrender" button to end the game at any time. If your opponent surrenders, the game will be ended, you'll get one victory point and opponent one loss point.
</li>
<li>
<b>abort</b><br/>
When your opponent becomes dead, i.e. does not log in for more than three weeks, you may use the "Abort game" button to end the game. In this case neither you nor your opponent gain victory or loss points - the score remains unchanged.
</li>
<li>
<b>finish</b><br/>
If your opponent doesn't make his turn for more than three weeks and he doesn't become dead, you may use the "Finish game" button to end the game. In this case you'll get one victory point and opponent one loss point.
</li>
</ul>

<h4>Cards</h4>
<p><img style="float: right" src="img/screen_card.png" alt="card"/>Every card has a name, a price and an effect. The name and the price are found in the upper part of the card, the effect in the lower part, below the card picture. The price is the ammount of resources needed for a card to be played, each type of resource represented by the color related to the resource. This ammount will be subtracted from the resource stock when the card is played. The card can only be played if you have enough resources to pay for its price. After a card is played, its effect will take place. Every card belongs to some group, indicated by the card's border color. There are three groups: Common, Uncommon and Rare. Common cards have green border, Uncommon brown and Rare yellow. Every player has exactly eight cards in his or hers hand. Your cards are located at the upper part of the screen. Opponent's cards are located in the bottom part of the screen. You can see enemy's cards in his or hers hand. Some cards in yours/opponent's hand are marked with "New card" flag. This indicates that this card has been received to the hand only recently. You may want to pay close attention to these cards. In the middle of the game screen are cards last played by each player (it can be very important). In one turn one player plays one card or a player can discard a card instead of playing it. When a card is discarded, its cost is not payed, but its effect will not happen. After a card(s) has been played or discarded a new card(s) will be added to player's hand. The new card will be chosen randomly from the card groups with probabilities 65% for Common, 29% for Uncommon and 6% for Rare, unless a played card says otherwise. Rares can't be drawn by discarding effect of Common cards. Rares can't be drawn after <b>Quick</b> or <b>Swift</b> cards.</p>

<p>When drawing new card, the system takes into account cards on current player's hand. The system reduces the probability of stocking multiple instances of the same card in hand by doing this procedure:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Draw a random card according to the current rules (depends on draw procedure type)</li>
	<li>Count number of instances (= N) of new card already present in hand (played position doesn't count)</li>
	<li>Select the new card as chosen with probability of 1/(2^{N}) (i.e. reject the new card with probability of 1 - (1/(2^{N}))</li>
	<li>If a card was rejected return to 1, if it was chosen end procedure</li>
</ol>

<p>The probability that you will end up with multiple card instances is exponentially decreasing with number of instances. We call this the anti-flood mechanism. Let's look at some examples:</p>

<ul>
	<li>If there are no card instances (N = 0), the card is chosen with 100% probability</li>
	<li>If there is one card instance (N = 1), the card is chosen with 50% probability</li>
	<li>If there are two card instances (N = 2), the card is chosen with 25% probability</li>
	<li>If there are three card instances (N = 3), the card is chosen with 12.5% probability</li>
	<li>If there are four card instances (N = 4), the card is chosen with 6.25% probability</li>
</ul>

<p>Some cards have modes. If a card has more modes, it means it can be played with different effects. The effects are described on the card. For example card Merchant will add 6 bricks, when played in Mode1, 5 gems when played in Mode2 or 5 recruits, when played in mode3. When you can play such card, there is a mode selector next to the play button. Simply select the chosen mode of the card and play it. Some cards discard other cards from yours or opponents hand. Cards that where discarded during your last round are located to the left of the card history. Cards that were discarded during opponent's last round are shown to the right of the card history. One pile of discarded cards are further divided into cards that were discarded from your hand (located on the left of yellow vertical line) and cards that were discarded from opponent's hand (located on the right of yellow vertical line). Both card history and discarded cards are ordered in this fashion: last played/discarded are the leftmost.
</p>

<h4>Turn - actions</h4>
<ol>
	<li>Cost of a card is substracted</li>
	<li>Effect of the card takes place</li>
	<li>Keywords with side-effects apply</li>
	<li>Game limits apply (resources cannot be lower then 0, wall below 0, facitlies below 1...)</li>
	<li>Resource production</li>
	<li>End game condition is checked</li>
</ol>

<h4>Chat</h4>
<p>
You can chat with other players in the game screen.
Simply write the text in the bottom part of the game and then click the "Send message" button.
For more comfort you can use some hot keys.
Push Tab (or Alt+a when your browser support keybord shortcuts) to jump into chat window, write the message and then push Tab+Enter (or Alt+s).
The message itself contains the date and time when it was written and also name of the player who wrote it.
</p>

<h4>Deck building</h4>
<p>Deck section contains list of all decks. For each deck it is possible to see date and time of last modification, so you can tell how old each deck is. To enter deck details use the [&rarr;] button. If deck is ready for use (contains 45 cards), its name is highlighted in green color.</p>
<p>
<a style="float: right;" href="img/screen_deck_building.png"><img src="img/screen_deck_building_s.png" alt="deck building section"/></a>
Deck consists of 15 different cards from each group. A deck name must be different to all your other decks. Deck building section consits of control bar, where buttons that provide deck modifications and card pool modifications (filters), are located. On the left part this bar, there are filters. You can use them to filter out the unnecessary cards from the card pool. When a filter is active, it's border color is highlighted with lime color. There are five filters (all of them can be combined):</p>

<ul>
	<li>Class filter - selects either Common, Uncommon or Rare cards</li>
	<li>Keyword filter - selects cards that have specified keyword</li>
	<li>Cost filter - selects cards that have specified cost</li>
	<li>Advanced filter - selects cards that have specified card effect</li>
	<li>Support filter - selects cards that are supportive for selected keyword (i.e. they have the selected keyword mentioned in the card effect text)</li>
</ul>

<p>Just set the filters and then push the "Apply filters" button. On the right part of the bar, there are following buttons: Rename, Reset and Finish. To rename deck, simply write the name in the text window and click the "Rename deck" button. If you want to empty your deck just push the "Reset" button. When you don't want to build the deck yourself you can generate a random deck by pressing the "Randomize" button. "Finish" button will fill all remaining empty slots in your deck with random cards. Finnaly the rightmost is the average cost indicator. It shows you the average price of card per turn. Please do note that this calculation does only take into account card cost, not it's effect. Below is your deck.  When bulding a deck, each of the 45 card slots is occupied either by some card or just with an 'Empty' card (signalling an empty card slot). You can transfer a card from card pool by pushing Take button under the card you want to select. If you want to remove a card from your deck push the Return button under the card you whish to be removed. Any changes to the deck are immediately recorded, so it is possible to leave the deck incomplete. Such a deck cannot be used to play a game, though. When starting a game you must choose a deck from the deck list by selecting its name. There is a maximum of eight decks total for one player.
</p>

<p>To save deck slots, player can export decks into data files with "Export" button. When such exported deck is needed, player can load it from data file with "Import" button.</p>

<h4>New game</h4>
<p>
You can start a new game in two ways.
First, you can challenge someone to a game by selecting the challenge button in the User screen, which is in the same line as the player, who you want to challenge. The other option is to go to player's details and challenge him from there.
Then you need to choose the deck with which you want to play the game.
Second, you can wait until someone else challenges you and then accept the challenge.
Before accepting the challenge you also need to choose a deck, with which you want to play.
The player which goes first is randomly chosen. To compensate for disadvantage of going second, the other player is given one from each resource in addition to his starting stock.
There is a limit of max. 15 <i>simultaneous</i> games (this also includes hosted games), and only one game per opponent which you initiated (this implies that you can only have 2 parallel games against each person).
Incoming and outgoing challenges count as games, so try to accept or reject them as soon as possible.
There is no restriction to the number of games played per day or against someone, you can play any way you like.
</p>
<p>Alternative way to start a game is to host a game. This can be done in the games section. Select game modes and then use the "Host game" button. When game is hosted any player can join and then the game starts. This way you don't choose the opponent, but the opponent chooses you. When you host or join a game, you must select one of your decks. In both cases the deck selector is located above the games list on the left.</p>
<p>When you have a game where your turn is, it is indicated by animated image ("crossed swords") in the upper part of the screen (navigation bar).</p>

<p>It is possible to choose from several game modes, when starting a new game:</p>
<ul>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/blind.png" alt="blind flag" class="country_flag" /> Hide opponent's cards - this mode will disable the ability to see opponent's cards for both players</li>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/friendly_play.png" alt="friendly flag" class="country_flag" /> Friendly play - allows to play games, where the game outcome doesn't effect score or experience of the players</li>
</ul>

<p>Each player can configure his status in settings section. Player status can be seen by other players and can be used to help you find the desired opponent. There are four options available:</p>
<ul>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/ready.png" alt="status flag" class="country_flag" /> Looking for game - you want to play a normal game</li>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/quick.png" alt="status flag" class="country_flag" /> Looking for quick game - you want to play a quick game (play online until the game finishes without interruptions)</li>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/dnd.png" alt="status flag" class="country_flag" /> Do not disturb - you don't want to play games right now</li>
	<li><img width="20px" height="14px" src="img/noob.png" alt="status flag" class="country_flag" /> Newbie - new player, this is the default setting</li>
</ul>
<p>For example if you want to play a quick game, select "Looking for quick game" status. It is possible to use filter in players list section to filter out players with a specific status, so in this case, only players that are looking for a quick game.</p>

<h4>Messages</h4>
<p>
In the section "Messages" all challenges and messages that you received are located. When a new challenge/message arrives, you are informed about this in the upper menu bar with a animated image ("letter"). New messages can be written in the players section by selecting the [m] button or in the player's details section. Also you can reply to any message by selecting the reply button.
</p>

<p>
Messages have a "new message" notification system. New messages are highlighted in red color, but this only works correctly if you logout every time you finish your stay at our site. The messages can have various color information:
</p>

<ul>
	<li>Red - new messages</li>
	<li>Orange - unread messages</li>
	<li>Blue - battle report messages</li>
	<li>Lime - other messages</li>
</ul>

<h4>Player rating system</h4>

<p>Players gather experience by playing games. When enough experience is gathered, a player will gain a new level. Higher level ensures a higher place in the ladder of all players and grants extra game and deck slots. Each 4th level grants a bonus game slot and each 6th level grants bonus deck slot. Based on player's performance in the game, the experience amount is calculated. To level up on the Nth level you need 500 + (50 * N) + (200 * [N/5]) + (100 * [N/10]^{2}) EXP. The [] is operation floor, which is nearest lower integer number (for exmaple: [1] = 1, [1.3] = 1, [1.9] = 1, [2.2] = 2). Base EXP for one game is 100 EXP. Experience calculation is divided into four phases.</p>

<h4>First phase: Game rating</h4>
<p>From the perspective of one player the game can have several outcomes, each of them is handled separately. Below, there is a list of experience modifiers - one for each game outcome. This modifier applies onto the base EXP.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Victory - Resource accumulation: 115%</li>
	<li>Victory - Tower building: 110%</li>
	<li>Victory - Tower destruction: 105%</li>
	<li>Victory - Abandon: 100%</li>
	<li>Victory - Surrender: 95%</li>
	<li>Victory - Timeout: 60%</li>
	<li>Draw: 50%</li>
	<li>Loss - Timeout: 40%</li>
	<li>Loss - Tower destruction: 15%</li>
	<li>Loss - Tower building: 10%</li>
	<li>Loss - Resource accumulation: 5%</li>
	<li>Loss - Surrender: 0%</li>
	<li>Loss - Abandon: 0%</li>
</ul>

<p>For example, if Player1 won with Tower destruction victory, he will gain 105EXP. His opponent will gain only 15EXP. Lets give one more example. Player1 won with Timeout victory, he will gain 60EXP. His opponent will gain 40EXP. This EXP, which we recently computed, is not the EXP the players gain. This is the input to the next phase.</p>

<h4>Second phase: Opponent rating</h4>

<p>This phase deals with players' levels. The idea behind this phase is really simple. When you beat an opponent of higher level than yours, you get EXP bonus. On the other hand if you beat opponent of lower level than yours, you get EXP penalty.</p>

<ul>
	<li>If opponent's level is higher than yours, you get 10% EXP bonus for each opponent's level above yours. The amount of bonus is limited to 100% max.</li>
	<li>If opponent's level is same as yours, you don't get EXP bonus or EXP penalty.</li>
	<li>If opponent's level is lower than yours, you get 5% EXP penalty for each of your level that you are above opponent. The amount of penalty is limited to 50% max.</li>
</ul>

<p>Let's see an example. We take Player1 with 105 EXP. Player1 has level 7, Player2 has level 1. Now, let's compute the outcome. Player1 is 6 levels above Player2, so he gets 6 * 5% penalty, so it's 30% EXP penalty total. That leaves him with 105 * 0.7 =  74EXP (rounded). Player2 gets a bonus for 6 levels. He gets 6 * 10% bonus, 60% EXP bonus total. That leaves him with 10 * 1.6 = 24EXP.</p>

<h4>Third phase: Victory rating</h4>

<p>Main idea is to rate how close the victory was. The condition depends on the victory type. There are three victory ratings:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Major achievement - 75% EXP bonus</li>
	<li>Minor achievement - 25% EXP bonus</li>
	<li>Tactical achievement - no EXP bonus</li>
</ul>

<p>Table below explains how are victory ratings achieved. The system evaluates how close the victory was, by rating how close it was for each victory type. There are two cases, each explained separately.</p>

<h4>In case of victory</h4>

<p>Minimum is computed from all victory ratings. For example, if Resource accumulation was evaluated "Major", Tower building was evaluated "Minor" and Tower destruction was evaluated "Minor", the final result will be "Minor". If you want to achieve Major victory you need to satisfy condition for Major victory of all three types.</p>

<table class="centered skin_text" cellpadding="5">
	<tr>
		<td></td>
		<th>Major</th>
		<th>Minor</th>
		<th>Tactical</th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Resource accumulation</th>
		<td>Enemy stock below 150</td>
		<td>Enemy stock between 150 and 300</td>
		<td>Enemy stock above 300</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower building</th>
		<td>Enemy tower below 30</td>
		<td>Enemy tower between 30 and 60</td>
		<td>Enemy tower above 60</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower destruction</th>
		<td>Tower above 60</td>
		<td>Tower between 30 and 60</td>
		<td>Tower below 30</td>
	</tr>
</table>

<h4>In case of draw or loss</h4>

<p>Maximum is computed from all victory ratings. For example, if Resource accumulation was evaluated "Major", Tower building was evaluated "Minor" and Tower destruction was evaluated "Minor", the final result will be "Major". If you want to achieve Major victory you need to satisfy condition for Major victory of at least one of the three types.</p>

<table class="centered skin_text" cellpadding="5">
	<tr>
		<td></td>
		<th>Major</th>
		<th>Minor</th>
		<th>Tactical</th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Resource accumulation</th>
		<td>Stock above 300</td>
		<td>Stock between 150 and 300</td>
		<td>Stock below 150</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower building</th>
		<td>Tower above 60</td>
		<td>Tower between 30 and 60</td>
		<td>Tower below 30</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower destruction</th>
		<td>Enemy tower below 30</td>
		<td>Enemy tower between 30 and 60</td>
		<td>Enemy tower above 60</td>
	</tr>
</table>

<h4>Fourth phase: Awards</h4>

<p>This phase effects only the victor and allows you to gather extra EXP when certain conditions are satisfied. Any number of awards can be collected.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Gentle touch (20% EXP) - win by playing a common card</li>
	<li>Desolator (30% EXP) - win while enemy facilities = 1</li>
	<li>Titan (45% EXP) - win with the <b>Titan</b> set</li>
	<li>Assassin (50% EXP) - win within 10 rounds</li>
	<li>Collector (70% EXP) - win with at least 4 rare cards in hand (played card doesn't count)</li>
	<li>Builder (80% EXP) - win with maximum wall</li>
	<li>Survivor (90% EXP) - win with 1 tower and 0 wall</li>
</ul>

<p>After the game the system will send you a message about the outcome of the game - a game report (when battle reports option is active). It will show you how much EXP you got in each phase and how much EXP did you get in the end. Also, when you gain next level, the system will sent you an information message about it.</p>

<h4>Avatar</h4>
<p>
In the settings section you can upload your own avatar. Avatar must be a jpg, jpeg, png or gif image type, must have at most 10kB and should be 60px X 60px large. If it isn't, it will be resized to this size. Avatars with inappropriate content will be deleted and could also lead to ban.
</p>

<h4>Card terminology</h4>
<ul>
	<li>Stock - all three types of resource (Bricks, Gems, Recruits)</li>
	<li>Facilities - all three types of production (Quarry, Magic, Dungeon)</li>
	<li>If we are talking about Tower, Wall, Stock, Facilites ... etc. we are talking about your Tower Wall ... . Opponent's Tower, Wall ... are addresed as Enemy tower, Enemy wall ...</li>
	<li>Last card played means last card played by you not the opponent. Opponents last card played is addresed as last card played by opponent</li>
	<li>Production x0, Production x2, Production x3 - you will get zero production, double production, triple production this turn. Note that with the combination of some keyword effect (<b>Alliance</b>) you may get Production x2 two times (one becuase of card effect and one becuase of keyword effect). In this case the production factor is multiplied, so the result is Production x4.</li>
	<li>"Last card" means last card played or discarded by you (if more cards were played this round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Last card played" means last card played by you (if more cards were played this round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Last card played by opponent" means last card played by opponent (if opponent played more cards in his round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Recently discarded" means cards discarded by you last round or by opponent (during his last round)</li>
	<li>"Last round" is a round recently made by some player, cards that refer to changes made by opponent during his last round must be played at the start of the round, otherwise they will have no effect</li>
	<li>"(max N), (min N)" these are limits applied to each resource type (Bricks, Gems, Recruits). It means that you cannot get more then N of each resource for example.</li>
	<li>"#Keyword" means number of such keywords either in card present in your hand or in both player's hands (this is specified in the card effect description)</li>
	<li>"#Keyword1 + #Keyword2" means number of keywords1 plus number of keywords2, note that they are counted independently</li>
	<li>All decimal numbers are always rounded standard fashion way</li>
	<li>"If New" condition is satysfied when the played card had the "NEW CARD" flag above</li>
	<li>"matching card" is the card in opponent's hand which is in the same position as played card</li>
</ul>

<h4>Forum</h4>
<p>
Please use English only at all times. Forum is divided into sections. Section contains threads - discussions about some topic. There are 3 types of threads:
</p>
<ul>
	<li>Sticky - (red color) these are always at the top of the threadds list</li>
	<li>Important - (orange color) these are more important then other threads</li>
	<li>Normal - (white color) all other threads</li>
</ul>

<p>
Forum has a "new post" notification system. If there are new posts in the forum there is an animated image ("book") in the upper menu bar. Threads that contain new posts have the quick access buttons highlighted in red border color. In the threads details, new posts have their date highlighted in yellow color. This system works correctly only if you logout every time you finish your stay at our site.
</p>

<h4>Concepts</h4>
<p>
This section provides a tool for managing card suggestion in a structured form. This includes creating new cards, editing or deleting the existing ones. To provide more comfort, while searching for a specific card, there are filters and orderings available. You can even read the developer's feedback from the card state. There are 3 possible card states:
</p>
<ul>
	<li>Waiting - this is the initial state, card is waiting for analysis</li>
	<li>Interesting - card has a higher probability of beeing implemented</li>
	<li>Implemented - card has already been implemented</li>
	<li>Rejected - card will not be implemented in current form</li>
</ul>

<h4>Card template</h4>

<p>To create new cards in the Concepts section, that are actually implementable, you need to follow certain restrictions. For example a card effect must be done in a single turn. Continuous effects are not supported. A card can only use/effect data described below:</p>

<p>Game data (both player and opponent has their own data with the exception of round)</p>

<ul>
	<li>Tower</li>
	<li>Wall</li>
	<li>Quarry</li>
	<li>Magic</li>
	<li>Dungeon</li>
	<li>Bricks</li>
	<li>Gems</li>
	<li>Recruits</li>
	<li>Round</li>
	<li>Changes done previous round (can be used only at the start of each round, contains data about Tower, Wall Facilities and resources)</li>
	<li>Tokens</li>
	<li>Production factor for each facility (default value is 1, multiplies with keyword side-effects)</li>
</ul>

<p>Card history - cards played during this/previous round</p>
<p>Discarded cards:</p>

<ul>
	<li>dicarded by card effect during last round from player's hand</li>
	<li>dicarded by card effect during last round from opponent's hand</li>
	<li>dicarded by standard discard action</li>
</ul>

<p>Card data</p>

<ul>
	<li>Bricks</li>
	<li>Gems</li>
	<li>Recruits</li>
	<li>Keywords and effect (supports all filter conditions that are in the deck section). Keywords can have one parameter (like Charge), but it cannot be dynamic.</li>
	<li>New card flag (whether the card is new or not)</li>
	<li>Reveal flag (used only in games with hidden cards)</li>
	<li>Tokens</li>
</ul>

<p>Unsupported card effects</p>

<ul>
	<li>continuous card effects (effects that manipulate future turns)</li>
	<li>using card effects of other cards</li>
	<li>card effects based on results of the keyword effects</li>
</ul>

<h4>Keywords</h4>
<p>
Keywords represent information about the card that is too big to fit in the card box, or some property that other cards may look for while performing their effect. Below, all keywords are listed and explained.
</p>

<ul>
	<li><b>Alliance</b> - basic gain 17, bonus gain 3, side-effect (Arcane knowledge): additional Production x2.</li>
	<li><b>Aqua</b> - if an <b>Aqua</b> card is played after playing a different, non-common <b>Aqua</b> card, it raises your tower and wall by 5, opponent's stock is reduced by 5.</li>
	<li><b>Banish</b> - discards one random <b>Durable</b> card from enemy hand (if there is one). Common cards can discard common and uncommon cards, uncommon cards can discard any rarity. Rare cards can also discard any rarity, but they have additional effect (player gains stock equal to discarded card cost). Cards with highest discardable rarity are preferred. Cards that cannot be discarded by played card are not considered targets for discard.</li>
	<li><b>Barbarian</b> - basic gain 4, bonus gain 15, side-effect (Devastation): enemy wall will be additionally lowered by ammount based on played card rarity (Common - 3 , Uncommon -  8, Rare - 15).</li>
	<li><b>Brigand</b> - basic gain 10, bonus gain 10, side-effect (Robbery): additional stock will be stolen from opponent, ammount based on played card rarity (Common - 1 stock, Uncommon -  2 stock, Rare - 3 stock).</li>
	<li><b>Beast</b> - basic gain 14, bonus gain 10, side-effect (Fierce attack): additional damage will be inflicted upon your enemy based on played card rarity (Common - 2 , Uncommon -  5, Rare - 10).</li>
	<li><b>Burning</b> - basic gain 3, bonus gain 11, side-effect (Fire blast): replaces one random non-<b>Burning</b> card from enemy hand (if there is one) with Searing fire. Can only replace a card with same or lower rarity as was the played card, but cards with highest replacable rarity are preferred. Cards that cannot be replaced by played card are not considered targets for replace.</li>
	<li><b>Charge</b> - when card has this keyword, it also has a number next to this keyword. When such card is played and the opponent's wall (after the standard attack) is 0, he will receive additional damage equal to number next to charge.</li>
	<li><b>Destruction</b> - if an <b>Destruction</b> card is played after playing a different, non-common <b>Destruction</b> card, it reduces enemy's highest facility by 1 when it is greater then 3, otherwise it reduces opponent's highest resurce by 10.</li>
	<li><b>Dragon</b> - if there is another <b>Dragon</b> in hand, next card will be Dragon egg (if there is no Dragon egg card in hand) or Gems production x2 (if there already is a Dragon egg card in hand).</li>
	<li><b>Durable</b> - card stays on hand.</li>
	<li><b>Enduring</b> - when card has this keyword, it also has a number next to this keyword. When such card is played and the last card played was same as this one, opponent will suffer additional damage equal to number next to Enduring.</li>
	<li><b>Flare attack</b> - when played, one player receives Searing fire cards at odd card positions, while the other player receives Searing fire cards at even card positions. Who receives odd and who even positions is resolved randomly. The position of the played card is ignored and <b>Burning</b> cards are not replaced by Searing fires. Rare cards aren't replaced, unless the played card is a rare.</li>
	<li><b>Frenzy</b> - if there is another <b>Frenzy</b> card in hand, opponent receives bonus damage (recruits cost of the played card).</li>
	<li><b>Holy</b> - basic gain 25, bonus gain 5, side-effect (Purification): replaces one random <b>Undead</b> card from enemy hand (if there is one) with Purified ashes. Can only replace a card with same or lower rarity as was the played card, but cards with highest replacable rarity are preferred. Cards that cannot be replaced by played card are not considered targets for replace. You will get additional stock based on replaced card rarity (Common - 1 stock, Uncommon -  2 stock, Rare - 3 stock).</li>
	<li><b>Illusion</b> - if an <b>Illusion</b> card is played after playing a different, non-common <b>Illusion</b> card, next card will be a rare card from enemy deck.</li>
	<li><b>Legend</b> - if there is a rare card in hand (other then played card) raises random facility by one.</li>
	<li><b>Mage</b> - basic gain 10, bonus gain 3, side-effect (Willpower): If (Magic - Enemy magic &lt; 2) Magic: +1 else Gems: +10</li>
	<li><b>Nature</b> - if an <b>Nature</b> card is played after playing a different, non-common <b>Nature</b> card, next card will be a rare <b>Nature</b> card.</li>
	<li><b>Quick</b> - player gets an additional turn, but no production this turn, it is impossible to draw a rare card after a <b>Quick</b> card is played.</li>
	<li><b>Rebirth</b> - when played and number of <b>Burning</b> cards in game is greater then 3, the card stays on hand and you will get additional 16 gems.</li>
	<li><b>Restoration</b> - if an <b>Restoration</b> card is played after playing a different, non-common <b>Restoration</b> card, it raises your lowest facility by 1 when your facility is below 3, otherwise it gives you 10 of your lowest resource.</li>
	<li><b>Skirmisher</b> - discards one random <b>Charge</b> card from enemy hand (if there is one). Common cards can discard common and uncommon cards, uncommon cards can discard any rarity. Rare cards can also discard any rarity, but they have additional effect (opponent loses stock equal to discarded card cost). Cards with highest discardable rarity are preferred. Cards that cannot be discarded by played card are not considered targets for discard.</li>
	<li><b>Soldier</b> - basic gain 15, bonus gain 10, side-effect (Veteran troops): half of the recruits cost of the played card will be returned.</li>
	<li><b>Swift</b> - player gets additional turn, also with production, it is impossible to draw a rare card after a <b>Swift</b> card is played.</li>
	<li><b>Titan</b> - basic gain 22, bonus gain 5, side-effect (Titan's will): next card received will be a <b>Titan</b>.</li>
	<li><b>Undead</b> - basic gain 5, bonus gain 5, side-effect (Eternal servitude): third of the total cost of the played card will be returned.</li>
	<li><b>Unliving</b> - basic gain 9, bonus gain 8, side-effect (Artificial workers): additional bricks production based on played card rarity (Common - x2, Uncommon - x3, Rare - x4).</li>
</ul>

<p>Keywords are divided into two groups - category and effect keywords. Category keywords are executed as first, effect keywords, as second. Here is an order of keyword execution within each group (keywords on cards are listed in such order):</p>

<h4>Category keywords</h4>

<ol>
	<li>Alliance</li>
	<li>Aqua</li>
	<li>Barbarian</li>
	<li>Beast</li>
	<li>Brigand</li>
	<li>Burning</li>
	<li>Destruction</li>
	<li>Dragon</li>
	<li>Holy</li>
	<li>Illusion</li>
	<li>Legend</li>
	<li>Mage</li>
	<li>Nature</li>
	<li>Restoration</li>
	<li>Soldier</li>
	<li>Titan</li>
	<li>Undead</li>
	<li>Unliving</li>
</ol>

<h4>Effect keywords</h4>

<ol>
	<li>Durable</li>
	<li>Quick</li>
	<li>Swift</li>
	<li>Banish</li>
	<li>Skirmisher</li>
	<li>Rebirth</li>
	<li>Flare attack</li>
	<li>Frenzy</li>
	<li>Enduring</li>
	<li>Charge</li>
</ol>

<h4>Tokens</h4>
<p>
Some keywords have a side-effect, that requires a token counter. Player can choose up to three token counters for each deck in the deck section. It is possible to assign the token counters automatically by selecting the "Auto" button. Playing a card with keyword, which is associated with the token counter, will raise the value of the token counter. The number of tokens received varies with each keyword (see the Keyword section above). When a token counter reaches 100 a side-effect will happen and the token counter will be reseted to 0. This side-effect takes place directly after the card effect of the played card. Each token-associated keyword has a token gain. This information tells you how many tokens are gained when card with such keyword is played. Token gain consists of basic gain (number of tokens you get for the played card) and bonus gain (number of tokens you gain for each additional card in hand with the same keyword as the played card). Keywords with high basic gain are generally better used as support keywords, since they don't require to have many cards with the same keyword in hand, however their token gains might not be very high. Keywords with high bonus gain require many cards with the same keyword, but when there are such cards in hand, token gains can be very high.
</p>

<p>
Let's take the <b>Alliance</b> keyword for example. First you need to set one token counter to <b>Alliance</b> keyword (in the deck section). Then you normally start a game with this deck. <b>Alliance</b> keyword has 17 basic gain and 3 bonus gain. So, when you play a card that has <b>Alliance</b> keyword, it will raise the <b>Alliance</b> token counter by 17 plus 3 for each additional <b>Alliance</b> card in hand. When the counter reaches 100, it will add a Production x2 to the effect of the played card and will be reseted to 0. By paying close attention to the token counters, you will be able to make good combos of card effects and keyword side-effects. For example <b>Soldier</b> and Ceremonial guard or <b>Alliance</b> and Stilshrine of Miriam can make good stock boosting combos.
</p>

<h4>Color information</h4>

<p>Some information is not presented in a text form, but is encoded into text color. Here is a list of the semantics of different text colors you may encounter throughout the game.</p>

<ul>
	<li>In the players section, player name color holds the information about player's activity
		<ul>
			<li><b>Lime</b> (or <b>Green</b>) (online) means that player was active in last 10 minutes. This kind of information can be found in other sections too, for example challenges and games (in here game buttons have italic font style)</li>
			<li><b>Red</b> (offline) means that player was active in last 7 days</li>
			<li><b>Dark red</b> (inactive) means that player was active in last 21 days</li>
			<li><b>Gray</b> (dead) means that player was inactive for more than 21 days</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
	<li>In the game section color holds information about player activity. Opponent's name (located above tower and wall info) is in <b>Lime</b> (or <b>Green</b>) color, when he is online</li>
</ul>

<h4>Menubar notification</h4>

<p>By default, player is informed about new posts in the forum and new card concepts in the concepts section with small animated images in the upper navigation bar. This can be turned off in the settings section.</p>

<h4>Settings</h4>

<p>In this section you may customize MArcomage. Profile settings contain information about player identity, none of them is mandatory. When filled in, all other players are able to see this information. Account settings are used to adjust MArcomage to player's needs. It is possible to change password, set timezone, select skin and game background image. Menubar notification can be reset with "Reset notification" button (this will unmark all new posts and messages, it's the same as doing logout-login procedure). There are some layout options (described below).</p>

<h4>Layout options</h4>

<ul>
	<li>Auto refresh - when active, webpage is refreshed automatically in the selected time interval, this applies to games list section only</li>
	<li>Players list filter - determines default value of the players list filter</li>
	<li>Advanced games list - display more game details in the games list</li>
	<li>Minimized game view - remove some graphics in the game section to reduce screen space</li>
	<li>Show card text - display card effect text description</li>
	<li>Show card images - display card image (turn off on slow internet connection)</li>
	<li>Show card keywords - display card keywords text</li>
	<li>Show nationality in players list - display text description of players' nationality in the players list</li>
	<li>Reverse chat message order - reverses chat order in the chatbox (game section). By default chat messages are ordered from newest (top) to oldest (bottom)</li>
	<li>Show avatar in game - display avatar of both players in the game</li>
	<li>Show avatar in players list - display avatar in players list for all players who have an avatar</li>
	<li>Avatar display correction for chat - used to prevent Firefox 2.x display bug</li>
	<li>Old card appearance - display cards with old appearance</li>
	<li>Battle report messages - when active, system will automaticaly send private message to inform you about a game outcome (when it finishes) or when someone accepts or rejects your challenge</li>
	<li>Forum notification - display forum notification (new posts) in the menubar</li>
	<li>Concepts notification - display concepts notification (new concepts) in the menubar</li>
	<li>Random deck selection - allows to choose a random deck to play with when starting a game</li>
</ul>

<h4>Keyboard shortcuts</h4>
(might not work in some browsers without re-configuring them)
<ul>
	<li>ALT+s - send chat message</li>
	<li>ALT+a - set focus to chat window</li>
	<li>ALT+w - refresh button</li>
	<li>ALT+q - logout</li>
</ul>

</am:content>
</am:entry>
