<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--MArcomage game manual-->
<help xmlns="http://arcomage.netvor.sk">
	<part name="Introduction">
		<![CDATA[
<p>MArcomage (Multiplayer Arcomage) is an online card game inspired by original Arcomage. It's possible to play either against a human player or a computer player. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcomage">Arcomage</a> is a fantasy turn-based card game. This card game simulates an epic battle between two empires including features such as constructing new buildings, training troops and decimating the enemy empire with standard attacks or sneaky tactics such as intrigue or spells. There are similarities in gameplay, but there are differences in cards, game rules and victory conditions.</p>

<h4>Overview</h4>
<p>The game consists of rounds. Round consists of turns. In most cases one round consists of only one turn, but some cards allow player to make additional turns in the same round. In one turn a player can play one card. Then the next turn follows. After end of player's round it's his opponent's round, where he gets to play card(s). This way the players play the game - always one playing cards and the other one waiting for the next round where he can play cards. The cards themselves modify some attributes of the game (such as tower and wall height, resources ...). The game is very simple and easy to operate. There is much information on the game screen, we will now describe some basic information. In the upper left of the screen, your login name is written. In the upper part you can see the navigation bar, which is used to travel between sections.</p>

<p>In a game against a human player you have to wait until your opponent makes his move, so you can continue the game. In a game against a computer player you only need to push "Execute AI move" button to continue the game.</p>

<p>Right below the navigation bar you can see the round indicator, that keeps you informed in which round the game currently is. In the center-left part there is the "Next game" button. You can use it to traverse trough games, in which your turn is. "History" button is used to access game history (previuos rounds of the game). In the center of the screen you can see card history. There are no cards there at the beginning of the game, but later it will hold the card(s) recently played by you and your opponent. Above card history is the notice which informs you which player's turn currently is. When waiting for opponent's turn, you need to refresh the game with our refresh button. Furthermore if opponent's name (above the tower and wall information) is colored green it means that he is currently on-line.</p>

<p>To play or discard a card, you need to select the card first by clicking on the desired card (or clicking on the radio button below the card when JavaScript is disabled). Selected card is visualised by double black border. Then push either "Play" or "Discard" button, depending on the choice of action. Cards that can't be played because of insufficient resources are only partially visible. It's also possible to calculate changes that would be caused by playing the selected card, although these changes will be hypothetical in case of cards with random-based effect. This can be done with "Preview" button, which is operated the exact same way as "Play" button. However, "Preview" button works only if JavaScript is enabled and if hidden cards mode isn't used.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Tutorial">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Newly registered player starts in tutorial mode. While in tutorial, player is directed by visual guidance which helps him navigate the website. Some game sections are not available from the start. These sections are unlocked one at a time when player gains a new level. Game sections are unlocked on these levels:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Decks section - deck customization</li>
	<li>Cards section - card database viewer</li>
	<li>Replays section - game recordings database</li>
	<li>Novels section - fantasy novels</li>
	<li>Concepts section - new card suggestions by players</li>
	<li>Statistics section - card statistics and other game information</li>
</ol>

<p>In addition to unlocking new sections, player also unlocks cards in the process. The more cards are available to player, the more varied decks can he use. When player gains a new level, he receives level up message which informs him about the new features he just unlocked. Player gains experience points when playing against computer opponent while in tutorial, which is not the case for other players that already finished tutorial. Tutorial ends when player reaches level 10, all game sections and all cards are unlocked at this point.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Game attributes">
		<![CDATA[
<h4>Game attributes: Resources, facilities, resource production, tower and wall</h4>
<p>Every player has three types of resources: Bricks, Gems and Recruits, and three types of resource production facilities: Quarry, Magic and Dungeon (generating resources in the corresponding order). Bricks are the basic building material, used mostly for constructing buildings. Magic powered soul gems (shortly gems) represent the magical power at your disposal. And finally, recruits represent your living or fighting power (amount of creatures, soldiers and weapons). At the end of round, for each facility of certain type, one resource of the corresponding type is added to the active player's stock. Example: If Quarry = 3, at the end of round, three Bricks will be added to the stock. The number of facilities of any kind cannot drop below one, and the amount of a resource of a certain type cannot be lower than zero. Your resources and facilities are located in the center-left part of the screen. Opponent's resources and facilities are located in the center-right part of the screen.</p>
<p>Every player has his/her own tower and wall, each having a height. Tower height can be at most 100 (150 in long mode), wall has height limit 150 (225 in long mode). In the case of a standard enemy attack, the attack will first lower the wall. Only after the wall height is zero and some attack power still remains will the tower be lowered. Example: Enemy attacks with an attack power of 25, wall height is 10, tower height is 20. After the attack, the wall height will be zero and the tower height will be 5. There are some cards that do damage to the tower directly, bypassing the wall. Tower and wall information are located in the bottom-left part (yours) and bottom-right (opponent's). Moreover, if some of these game attributes were changed due to effect of some card, it will be indicated by a small number next to the effected attribute. Cost of a played card is not displayed in the changes.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Victory types">
		<![CDATA[			
<p>The goal of the game is to defeat your opponent by reaching one or more victory conditions. The following outcomes are possible:</p>
<ul>
	<li><b>tower destruction</b> - raze the enemy tower to the ground to win - meaning, lower the enemy tower to zero height. Usually achieved by green cards and standard attacks.</li>
	<li><b>tower building</b> - build up your tower to height 100 (150 in long mode) to win. Usually achieved by delaying enemy attacks while building your tower.</li>
	<li><b>resource accumulation</b> - accumulate 400 (600 in long mode) of resources (total sum) to win. Beware of cards that cripple your stock.</li>
	<li><b>timeout</b> - each game is limited to 250 (375 in long mode) rounds. Afterwards, both players' states are compared (in the order: tower, wall, no. of facilities, sum of resources). Whoever has more (in that order), wins. Otherwise the game is declared a draw.</li>
</ul>
<p>Special rules apply in the case where both players achieve a victory condition simultaneously. If the victory type for both is the same, the result is, logically, a draw. If the victory types are different, the following rule is used to determine the winner:</p>
<p>Destruction victory > Tower bulding victory > Resource victory > Timeout victory.</p>
<p>After the game is finished and a player leaves the game, his opponent is informed about this with "player has left the game" message in the chat window.</p>

<h4>Special game end types</h4>
<p>Game can be ended in different way when certain conditions are met.</p>
<ul>
	<li><b>surrender</b> - each player can use the "Surrender" button to send a surrender request to his opponent. Surrender request can be cancelled until the opponent accepts or rejects the request. The game will be ended only if he accepts. In such case, player who sent the surrender request will get one loss point and his opponent will get one victory point.</li>
	<li><b>abort</b> - when your opponent becomes dead, i.e. does not log in for more than three weeks, you may use the "Abort game" button to end the game. In this case neither you nor your opponent gain victory or loss points - the score remains unchanged.</li>
	<li><b>finish</b> - if your opponent doesn't make his turn for more than three weeks and he doesn't become dead, you may use the "Finish game" button to end the game. In this case you'll get one victory point and opponent one loss point.</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Cards">
		<![CDATA[
<p><img style="float: right" src="img/screen_card.png" alt="card"/>Every card has a name, a price and an effect. The name and the price are found in the upper part of the card, the effect in the lower part, below the card picture. The price is the amount of resources needed for a card to be played, each type of resource represented by the color related to the resource. This amount will be subtracted from the resource stock when the card is played. The card can only be played if you have enough resources to pay for its price. After a card is played, its effect will take place. Every card belongs to some group, indicated by the card's border color. There are three groups: Common, Uncommon and Rare. Common cards have green border, Uncommon brown and Rare yellow. Every player has exactly eight cards in his or hers hand. Your cards are located at the upper part of the screen. Opponent's cards are located in the bottom part of the screen. You can see enemy's cards in his or hers hand.</p>
<p>Some cards in yours/opponent's hand are marked with "New card" flag. This indicates that this card has been received to the hand only recently. You may want to pay close attention to these cards. In the middle of the game screen are cards last played by each player (it can be very important). In one turn one player plays one card or a player can discard a card instead of playing it. When a card is discarded, its cost is not payed, but its effect will not happen. After a card(s) has been played or discarded a new card(s) will be added to player's hand. The new card will be chosen randomly from the card groups with probabilities 65% for Common, 29% for Uncommon and 6% for Rare, unless a played card says otherwise. Rares can't be drawn after <b>Quick</b> or <b>Swift</b> cards.</p>

<p>When drawing new card, the system takes into account cards on current player's hand. The system reduces the probability of stocking multiple instances of the same card in hand by doing this procedure:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Draw a random card according to the current rules (depends on draw procedure type)</li>
	<li>Count number of instances (= N) of new card already present in hand (played position doesn't count)</li>
	<li>Select the new card as chosen with probability of 1/(2^{N}) (i.e. reject the new card with probability of 1 - (1/(2^{N}))</li>
	<li>If a card was rejected return to 1, if it was chosen end procedure</li>
</ol>

<p>The probability that you will end up with multiple card instances is exponentially decreasing with number of instances. We call this the anti-flood mechanism. Let's look at some examples:</p>

<ul>
	<li>If there are no card instances (N = 0), the card is chosen with 100% probability</li>
	<li>If there is one card instance (N = 1), the card is chosen with 50% probability</li>
	<li>If there are two card instances (N = 2), the card is chosen with 25% probability</li>
	<li>If there are three card instances (N = 3), the card is chosen with 12.5% probability</li>
	<li>If there are four card instances (N = 4), the card is chosen with 6.25% probability</li>
</ul>

<p>Some cards have modes. If a card has more modes, it means it can be played with different effects. The effects are described on the card. For example card Merchant will add 6 bricks, when played in Mode1, 5 gems when played in Mode2 or 5 recruits, when played in mode3. When you can play such card, there is a mode selector next to the play button. Simply select the chosen mode of the card and play it. Some cards discard other cards from yours or opponents hand. Such cards are placed into the graveyard. Cards that where discarded during your last round are located to the left of the card history. Cards that were discarded during opponent's last round are shown to the right of the card history. One pile of discarded cards are further divided into cards that were discarded from your hand (located on the left of yellow vertical line) and cards that were discarded from opponent's hand (located on the right of yellow vertical line). Both card history and discarded cards are ordered in this fashion: last played/discarded are the leftmost.</p>

<p>Not all cards are available at the start of the game. Each player initially starts only with cards that are present in the starter decks. Each card has a level requirement. Only players with level greater or equal than the requirement will be able to use the card. Card level requirement of each card can be viewed in the <a href="?location=Cards">cards section</a>.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Card terminology">
		<![CDATA[
<ul>
	<li>Stock - all three types of resource (Bricks, Gems, Recruits)</li>
	<li>Facilities - all three types of production (Quarry, Magic, Dungeon)</li>
	<li>If we are talking about Tower, Wall, Stock, Facilites ... etc. we are talking about your Tower Wall ... . Opponent's Tower, Wall ... are addresed as Enemy tower, Enemy wall ...</li>
	<li>Last card played means last card played by you not the opponent. Opponents last card played is addresed as last card played by opponent</li>
	<li>Production x0, Production x2, Production x3 - you will get zero production, double production, triple production this turn. Note that with the combination of some keyword effect (<b>Alliance</b>) you may get Production x2 two times (one becuase of card effect and one becuase of keyword effect). In this case the production factor is multiplied, so the result is Production x4.</li>
	<li>Bricks prod, Gems prod, Recruits prod - represents production of one specific resource (Bricks, Gems, Recruits)</li>
	<li>Summons <b>Keyword</b> means that next card received will be a card with specified keyword</li>
	<li>"Last card" means last card played or discarded by you (if more cards were played this round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Last card played" means last card played by you (if more cards were played this round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Last card played by opponent" means last card played by opponent (if opponent played more cards in his round then it is the most recent one)</li>
	<li>"Recently discarded" means cards discarded by you last round or by opponent (during his last round)</li>
	<li>"Last round" is a round recently made by some player, cards that refer to changes made by opponent during his last round must be played at the start of the round, otherwise they will have no effect</li>
	<li>"(max N), (min N)" these are limits applied to each resource type (Bricks, Gems, Recruits). It means that you cannot get more than N of each resource for example.</li>
	<li>"#Keyword" means number of such keywords either in card present in your hand or in both player's hands (this is specified in the card effect description)</li>
	<li>"#Keyword1 + #Keyword2" means number of keywords1 plus number of keywords2, note that they are counted independently</li>
	<li>All decimal numbers are always rounded standard fashion way</li>
	<li>"If New" condition is satysfied when the played card had the "NEW CARD" flag above</li>
	<li>"matching card" is the card in opponent's hand which is in the same position as played card</li>
	<li>"Max tower" means maximum possible tower height which is 100 in normal mode and 150 in long mode</li>
	<li>"Max wall" means maximum possible wall height which is 150 in normal mode and 225 in long mode</li>
	<li>"in game" means present in the game you are currently playing with your opponent</li>
	<li>"persistent" card is a card that has "replace a card in hand with self" effect</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Card summoning">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Some cards have summoning effect when played. Such cards have "Summons" text in their effect description for example. In the summoning card description there are conditions present, which specify the card that can be possibly summoned. Possible conditions are same as filter options in the deck section:</p>

<ul>
	<li>card rarity filter (common, uncommon, rare)</li>
	<li>card keyword filter (selected keyword)</li>
	<li>card cost filter (bricks only, recruits only, gems only, mixed cost, zero cost)</li>
	<li>advanced filter (filter based on card effect - attack cards, wall building cards...)</li>
	<li>support filter (cards that have effect based on some keyword)</li>
</ul>

<p>Note that unlike standard drawing, card summoning picks the summoned card from the list of all possible cards (that match the filters) with equal probability. To see the list of all possible cards (that can be summoned) go to deck section, configure the filters accoring to summoning description and view the card list.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Turn actions">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Turn actions order of execution</p>
<ol>
	<li>card cost is subtracted</li>
	<li>token counters (if present) are updated based on card keywords</li>
	<li>card effect is executed</li>
	<li>game limits are applied</li>
	<li>keyword(s) effect is executed</li>
	<li>game limits are applied</li>
	<li>resource production is added to player's stock based on player's facilities</li>
	<li>end game condition is checked</li>
</ol>
<p>Game limits</p>
<ul>
	<li>facilities can't be lower than 1</li>
	<li>resources can't be lower than 0</li>
	<li>tower can't be lower than 0 or greater than 100 (150 in long mode)</li>
	<li>wall can't be lower than 0 or greater than 150 (225 in long mode)</li>
	<li>token counters can't be lower than 0 or greater than 100</li>
	<li>attack can't have a negative value</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Keywords">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Keywords represent information about the card that is too big to fit in the card box, or some property that other cards may look for while performing their effect. Card keywords are displayed either as a keyword insignia or as a bold text. The form depends on the "Show keyword insignias" setting in the settings section (insignia is the default setting). Keyword description is displayed when hovering over a card keyword with mouse cursor. Check the <a href="?location=Cards_keywords">full keywords list</a> for detailed information.</p>

<p>Keywords are executed this fixed order:</p>

<ol>
	<li>Alliance</li>
	<li>Aqua</li>
	<li>Barbarian</li>
	<li>Beast</li>
	<li>Brigand</li>
	<li>Burning</li>
	<li>Demonic</li>
	<li>Destruction</li>
	<li>Dragon</li>
	<li>Holy</li>
	<li>Illusion</li>
	<li>Legend</li>
	<li>Mage</li>
	<li>Nature</li>
	<li>Restoration</li>
	<li>Runic</li>
	<li>Soldier</li>
	<li>Titan</li>
	<li>Undead</li>
	<li>Unliving</li>
	<li>Durable</li>
	<li>Quick</li>
	<li>Swift</li>
	<li>Far sight</li>
	<li>Banish</li>
	<li>Skirmisher</li>
	<li>Horde</li>
	<li>Rebirth</li>
	<li>Flare attack</li>
	<li>Frenzy</li>
	<li>Aria</li>
	<li>Enduring</li>
	<li>Charge</li>
	<li>Siege</li>
</ol>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Tokens">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Some keywords have a side-effect, that requires a token counter. Player can choose up to three token counters for each deck in the deck section. It is possible to assign the token counters automatically by selecting the "Auto" button. When deck is completed and no token counters are set, token counters will be chosen automatically. Playing a card with keyword, which is associated with the token counter, will raise the value of the token counter. The number of tokens received varies with each keyword (see the Keyword section above). When a token counter reaches 100 or more by playing a card with that keyword a side-effect will happen and the token counter will be reset to 0. This side-effect takes place directly after the card effect of the played card. Each token-associated keyword has a token gain. This information tells you how many tokens are gained when card with such keyword is played. Token gain consists of basic gain (number of tokens you get for the played card) and bonus gain (number of tokens you gain for each additional card in hand with the same keyword as the played card). Keywords with high basic gain are generally better used as support keywords, since they don't require to have many cards with the same keyword in hand, however their token gains might not be very high. Keywords with high bonus gain require many cards with the same keyword, but when there are such cards in hand, token gains can be very high.</p>

<p>Let's take the <b>Alliance</b> keyword for example. First you need to set one token counter to <b>Alliance</b> keyword (in the deck section). Then you normally start a game with this deck. <b>Alliance</b> keyword has 17 basic gain and 3 bonus gain. So, when you play a card that has <b>Alliance</b> keyword, it will raise the <b>Alliance</b> token counter by 17 plus 3 for each additional <b>Alliance</b> card in hand. When the counter reaches 100, it will add a Production x2 to the effect of the played card and will be reset to 0. By paying close attention to the token counters, you will be able to make good combos of card effects and keyword side-effects. For example <b>Soldier</b> and <a href="?location=Cards_details&amp;card=102">Ceremonial guard</a> or <b>Alliance</b> and <a href="?location=Cards_details&amp;card=375">Stilshrine of Miriam</a> can make good stock boosting combos.</p>

<p>Let's look at another example. <a href="?location=Cards_details&amp;card=121">Luna the Sorceress</a> has both <b>Mage</b> and <b>Far sight</b> keywords. Under certain conditions <b>Far sight</b> keyword is able to raise the value of the <b>Mage</b> token counter as well. When Luna the Sorceress is played, following can happen:</p>

<ol>
	<li><b>Mage</b> keyword raises the value of the <b>Mage</b> token counter, but not to 100</li>
	<li><b>Far sight</b> keyword raises the value of the <b>Mage</b> token counter to 100</li>
	<li>the <b>Mage</b> keyword side effect is not triggered despite the fact, that <b>Mage</b> token counter reached 100</li>
</ol>

<p>Why? Keywords are always executed in a <a href="?location=Help&amp;help_part=Keywords">fixed order</a>. In this case <b>Mage</b> keyword first, <b>Far sight</b> keyword second. Only the <b>Mage</b> keyword can trigger its side-effect. When the effect took place, the <b>Mage</b> token counter value didn't reach 100. <b>Far sight</b> keyword raised it to 100 later, but too late for the side-effect to happen. In this case, you need to play another card with <b>Mage</b> keyword to activate the <b>Mage</b> keyword side-effect.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Deck building">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Deck section contains list of all decks. For each deck it is possible to see date and time of last modification, so you can tell how old each deck is. To enter deck details click on the deck name. If deck is ready for use (contains 45 cards), its name is highlighted in green color.</p>
<p>Deck consists of 15 different cards from each group. A deck name must be different to all your other decks. Deck building section consits of control bar, where buttons that provide deck modifications and card pool modifications (filters), are located. On the left part of this bar, there are filters. You can use them to filter out the unnecessary cards from the card pool. When a filter is active, it's border color is highlighted with lime color. There are five filters (all of them can be combined):</p>

<ul>
	<li>Class filter - selects either Common, Uncommon or Rare cards</li>
	<li>Keyword filter - selects cards that have specified keyword</li>
	<li>Cost filter - selects cards that have specified cost</li>
	<li>Advanced filter - selects cards that have specified card effect</li>
	<li>Support filter - selects cards that are supportive for selected keyword (i.e. they have the selected keyword mentioned in the card effect text)</li>
	<li>Creation date filter - selects cards that were added on a specific date</li>
	<li>Modification date filter - selects cards that were modified on a specific date</li>
</ul>

<p>Just set the filters and then push the "Apply filters" button. Number of cards per row can be customized in the Settings section. To hide/show card pool click on the Hide/Show card pool button. On the right part of the bar, there are following buttons: Rename and Reset. To rename deck, simply write the name in the text window and click the "Rename deck" button. If you want to empty your deck just push the "Reset" button. Finnaly the rightmost is the average cost indicator. It shows you the average price of card per turn. Please do note that this calculation does only take into account card cost, not it's effect. Below is your deck. When bulding a deck, each of the 45 card slots is occupied either by some card or just with an 'Empty' card (signalling an empty card slot). You can transfer a card from card pool by clicking on the card (or pushing Take button under the card you want to select when JavaScript is disabled).</p>

<p>If you want to remove a card from your deck, also click on the card (or push the Return button under the card when JavaScript is disabled) you whish to be removed. Any changes to the deck are immediately recorded, so it is possible to leave the deck incomplete. Such a deck cannot be used to play a game, though. When starting a game you must choose a deck from the deck list by selecting its name. There is a maximum of eight decks total for one player.</p>

<p>To save deck slots, player can export decks into data files with "Export" button. When such exported deck is needed, player can load it from data file with "Import" button.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="New game">
		<![CDATA[
<p>You can start a new game against a human player in two ways. First, you can challenge someone to a game by selecting the challenge button in the User screen, which is in the same line as the player, who you want to challenge. The other option is to go to player's details and challenge him from there. Then you need to choose the deck with which you want to play the game. Second, you can wait until someone else challenges you and then accept the challenge. Before accepting the challenge you also need to choose a deck, with which you want to play. The player which goes first is randomly chosen. To compensate for disadvantage of going second, the other player is given one from each resource in addition to his starting stock.</p>

<p>To start a game against a computer player use the "Quick game vs AI" button located in the games section. This way the game starts right away without the advanced game configuration which can be accessed via the "AI games" subsection. Computer player will use only starter decks, however it's also possible to give him one of your decks to play with. Please note that games against a computer player will have the Friendly play game mode always active.</p>

<p>There is a limit of max. 15 <i>simultaneous</i> games (this also includes hosted games). Incoming and outgoing challenges count as games, so try to accept or reject them as soon as possible. This limit can be raised by gaining higher levels. There is no restriction to the number of games played per day or against someone, you can play any way you like.</p>

<p>Alternative way to start a game is to host a game. This can be done in the games section. Select game modes and then use the "Host game" button. When game is hosted any player can join and then the game starts. This way you don't choose the opponent, but the opponent chooses you. When you host or join a game, you must select one of your decks. In both cases the deck selector is located above the games list on the left.</p>
<p>When you have a game where your turn is, it is indicated by animated image ("crossed swords") in the upper part of the screen (navigation bar).</p>

<p>It is possible to choose from several game modes, when starting a new game:</p>
<ul>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/blind.png" alt="Hidden cards" title="Hidden cards" /> Hide opponent's cards - this mode will disable the ability to see opponent's cards for both players</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/friendly_play.png" alt="Friendly play" title="Friendly play" /> Friendly play - allows to play games, where the game outcome doesn't effect score or experience of the players</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/long_mode.png" alt="Long mode" title="Long mode" /> Long mode - starting and maximum tower and wall values are higher (1.5 times), resource and timeout victory condition as well</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/ai_mode.png" alt="AI mode" title="AI mode" /> AI mode - game against a computer player (this mode will also activate Friendly play game mode)</li>
</ul>

<p>Each player can configure his status in settings section. Player status can be seen by other players and can be used to help you find the desired opponent. There are four options available:</p>
<ul>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/ready.png" alt="status flag" title="ready" /> Looking for game - you want to play a normal game</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/quick.png" alt="status flag" title="quick" /> Looking for quick game - you want to play a quick game (play online until the game finishes without interruptions)</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/dnd.png" alt="status flag" title="dnd" /> Do not disturb - you don't want to play games right now</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/newbie.png" alt="status flag" title="newbie" /> Newbie - new player, this is the default setting</li>
</ul>
<p>For example if you want to play a quick game, select "Looking for quick game" status. It is possible to use filter in players list section to filter out players with a specific status, so in this case, only players that are looking for a quick game. All icon images have their description displayed when hovering over them with mouse cursor.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="AI game">
		<![CDATA[
<p>In an AI game you play against a computer opponent. AI games have some restrictions that normal games don't. AI games are always played in Friendly play game mode, so their outcome doesn't effect player's score. Other restrictions depend on the AI game type.</p>

<ul>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/ai_mode.png" alt="AI mode" title="AI mode" />normal AI game - you are playing against normal AI, which uses starter deck by default and applies general strategy. You can also give the AI one of your own decks to play with by either random or manual selection.</li>
	<li><img class="icon" width="20px" height="14px" src="img/ai_challenge.png" alt="AI challenge" title="AI challenge" />AI challenge - you are playing against custom AI, which uses only one special deck. AI challenges are always played in Long game mode. AI challenges are more difficult because:
		<ul>
			<li>AI uses specialized strategy which is optimized for its deck</li>
			<li>AI starts with an advantage (resources and facilities)</li>
			<li>you can't play rare cards, although you can still draw them</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Player rating system">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Players gather experience by playing games. When enough experience is gathered, a player will gain a new level. Higher level ensures a higher place in the ladder of all players. Each time a player gains a new level, he also gains 100 gold as well (which can be used to buy additional game and deck slots in the Setting section at the MArcomage shop or to buy foil versions of cards in the Cards section). Based on player's performance in the game, the experience amount is calculated. To level up on the Nth level you need 500 + (50 * N) + (200 * [N/5]) + (100 * [N/10]^{2}) EXP. The [] is operation floor, which is nearest lower integer number (for exmaple: [1] = 1, [1.3] = 1, [1.9] = 1, [2.2] = 2). Base EXP for one game is 100 EXP and base gold is 0. Gold can be gained only in the fourth phase by gaining game awards. Rating system calculation is divided into four phases.</p>

<h4>First phase: Game rating</h4>
<p>From the perspective of one player the game can have several outcomes, each of them is handled separately. Below, there is a list of experience modifiers - one for each game outcome. This modifier applies onto the base EXP.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Victory - Resource accumulation: 115%</li>
	<li>Victory - Tower building: 110%</li>
	<li>Victory - Tower destruction: 105%</li>
	<li>Victory - Abandon: 100%</li>
	<li>Victory - Surrender: 95%</li>
	<li>Victory - Timeout: 60%</li>
	<li>Draw: 50%</li>
	<li>Loss - Timeout: 40%</li>
	<li>Loss - Tower destruction: 15%</li>
	<li>Loss - Tower building: 10%</li>
	<li>Loss - Resource accumulation: 5%</li>
	<li>Loss - Surrender: 0%</li>
	<li>Loss - Abandon: 0%</li>
</ul>

<p>For example, if Player1 won with Tower destruction victory, he will gain 105EXP. His opponent will gain only 15EXP. Lets give one more example. Player1 won with Timeout victory, he will gain 60EXP. His opponent will gain 40EXP. This EXP, which we recently computed, is not the EXP the players gain. This is the input to the next phase.</p>

<h4>Second phase: Opponent rating</h4>

<p>This phase deals with players' levels. The idea behind this phase is really simple. When you beat an opponent of higher level than yours, you get EXP bonus. On the other hand if you beat opponent of lower level than yours, you get EXP penalty.</p>

<ul>
	<li>If opponent's level is higher than yours, you get 10% EXP bonus for each opponent's level above yours. The amount of bonus is limited to 100% max.</li>
	<li>If opponent's level is same as yours, you don't get EXP bonus or EXP penalty.</li>
	<li>If opponent's level is lower than yours, you get 5% EXP penalty for each of your level that you are above opponent. The amount of penalty is limited to 50% max.</li>
</ul>

<p>Let's see an example. We take Player1 with 105 EXP. Player1 has level 7, Player2 has level 1. Now, let's compute the outcome. Player1 is 6 levels above Player2, so he gets 6 * 5% penalty, so it's 30% EXP penalty total. That leaves him with 105 * 0.7 =  74EXP (rounded). Player2 gets a bonus for 6 levels. He gets 6 * 10% bonus, 60% EXP bonus total. That leaves him with 10 * 1.6 = 24EXP.</p>

<h4>Third phase: Victory rating</h4>

<p>Main idea is to rate how close the victory was. The condition depends on the victory type. There are three victory ratings:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Major achievement - 75% EXP bonus</li>
	<li>Minor achievement - 25% EXP bonus</li>
	<li>Tactical achievement - no EXP bonus</li>
</ul>

<p>Table below explains how are victory ratings achieved. The system evaluates how close the victory was, by rating how close it was for each victory type. There are two cases, each explained separately.</p>

<h4>In case of victory</h4>

<p>Average victory is computed from all victory ratings, the result is rounded down. For example, if Resource accumulation was evaluated "Major", Tower building was evaluated "Minor" and Tower destruction was evaluated "Minor", the final result will be "Minor". If you want to achieve Major victory you need to satisfy condition for Major victory of all three types. Percentages below refer to:</p>

<ul>
	<li>stock compared to stock needed for resource accumulation victory</li>
	<li>tower compared to tower needed for tower building victory</li>
</ul>

<table class="centered skin_text" cellpadding="5">
	<tr>
		<td></td>
		<th>Major</th>
		<th>Minor</th>
		<th>Tactical</th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Resource accumulation</th>
		<td>Enemy stock below 33%</td>
		<td>Enemy stock between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Enemy stock above 66%</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower building</th>
		<td>Enemy tower below 33%</td>
		<td>Enemy tower between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Enemy tower above 66%</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower destruction</th>
		<td>Tower above 66%</td>
		<td>Tower between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Tower below 33%</td>
	</tr>
</table>

<h4>In case of draw or loss</h4>

<p>Average victory is computed from all victory ratings, the result is rounded up. For example, if Resource accumulation was evaluated "Major", Tower building was evaluated "Minor" and Tower destruction was evaluated "Minor", the final result will be "Major". Percentages below refer to:</p>

<ul>
	<li>stock compared to stock needed for resource accumulation victory</li>
	<li>tower compared to tower needed for tower building victory</li>
</ul>

<table class="centered skin_text" cellpadding="5">
	<tr>
		<td></td>
		<th>Major</th>
		<th>Minor</th>
		<th>Tactical</th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Resource accumulation</th>
		<td>Stock above 66%</td>
		<td>Stock between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Stock below 33%</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower building</th>
		<td>Tower above 66%</td>
		<td>Tower between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Tower below 33%</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<th>Tower destruction</th>
		<td>Enemy tower below 33%</td>
		<td>Enemy tower between 33% and 66%</td>
		<td>Enemy tower above 66%</td>
	</tr>
</table>

<h4>Fourth phase: Awards</h4>

<p>This phase effects only the victor and allows you to gather extra gold when certain conditions are satisfied. Any number of awards can be collected. Game state is examined at the end of the game.</p>

<ul>
	<li>Saboteur (1 gold) - opponent's tower is destroyed, but opponent's wall must not be completely destroyed</li>
	<li>Gentle touch (2 gold) - you played a common card on your last turn</li>
	<li>Desolator (3 gold) - opponent's facilities = 1</li>
	<li>Dragon (3 gold) - you played a <b>Dragon</b> on your last turn</li>
	<li>Carpenter (4 gold) - your every facility has at least double its starting value</li>
	<li>Titan (4 gold) - you played <a href="?location=Cards_details&amp;card=315">Completion ritual</a> on your last turn and game ended by Destruction victory</li>
	<li>Assassin (5 gold) - game ended within 10 rounds (20 rounds in long mode)</li>
	<li>Snob (6 gold) - you discarded a card on your last turn by standard discard action</li>
	<li>Collector (7 gold) - there are at least 4 rare cards in your hand (played card doesn't count)</li>
	<li>Builder (8 gold) - your wall is at maximum</li>
	<li>Survivor (9 gold) - you have 1 tower and 0 wall</li>
</ul>

<p>After the game the system will send you a message about the outcome of the game - a game report (when battle reports option is active). It will show you how much EXP or gold you got in each phase and how much EXP and gold did you get in the end. Also, when you gain next level, the system will sent you an information message about it.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Messages">
		<![CDATA[
<p>In the section "Messages" all challenges and messages that you received are located. When a new challenge/message arrives, you are informed about this in the upper menu bar with a animated image ("letter"). New messages can be written in the players section by selecting the [m] button or in the player's details section. Also you can reply to any message by selecting the reply button.</p>

<p>Messages have a "new message" notification system. New messages are highlighted in red color, but this only works correctly if you logout every time you finish your stay at our site. The messages can have various color information:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Red - new messages</li>
	<li>Orange - unread messages</li>
	<li>Blue - battle report messages</li>
	<li>Lime - other messages</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Chat">
		<![CDATA[
<p>You can chat with other players in the game screen. Chat can be opened by pushing the "Chat" button which is located in the upper left part of the screen. Simply write the text and then click the "Send" button. If there are new messages the "Chat" button will be highlighted and the new messages as well (once the chat is opened). Chat supports BBcode and multi-line messages similar to those on the Forum. The message itself contains the date and time when it was written and also name of the player who wrote it. Note that when chat is opened the auto-refresh is paused. After the chat is closed, the auto-refresh is resumed. In case JavaScript is disabled, alternative chat interface is located at the bottom of the game screen.</p>

<p>Chat can be configured to be integrated with the game screen in the settings section.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Forum">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Please be polite, present your arguments without verbal hostility between people (try not to use unnecessarily vulgar terms) and use English only at all times. Note that this site is intended for players of any age. Before posting, please make sure to use the forum search to check if there isn't already a thread about the topic you wish to discuss. You may also find the answer you seek in the <a href="?location=Webpage&amp;WebSection=Faq">FAQ</a>.</p>

<p>Forum is divided into sections. Section contains threads - discussions about some topic. There are 3 types of threads:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Sticky <img class="icon" src="img/sticky.gif" width="22px" height="15x" alt="sticky" title="Sticky" />- these are always at the top of the threads list</li>
	<li>Important <img class="icon" src="img/important.gif" width="18px" height="13px" alt="important" title="Important" />- these are more important than other threads</li>
	<li>Normal - all other threads</li>
</ul>

<p>Forum has a "new post" notification system. If there are new posts in the forum there is an animated image ("book") in the upper menu bar. Threads that contain new posts have the date and time of last post highlighted in red border color. In the threads details, new posts have their date highlighted in red color. This system works correctly only if you logout every time you finish your stay at our site.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Concepts">
		<![CDATA[
<p>This section provides a tool for managing card suggestion in a structured form. This includes creating new cards, editing or deleting the existing ones. To provide more comfort, while searching for a specific card, there are filters and orderings available. You can even read the developer's feedback from the card state. There are 3 possible card states:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Waiting - this is the initial state, card is waiting for analysis</li>
	<li>Interesting - card has a higher probability of beeing implemented</li>
	<li>Implemented - card has already been implemented</li>
	<li>Rejected - card will not be implemented in current form</li>
</ul>

<h4>Card picture</h4>

<p>We prefer card pictures to be in PNG format, although other formats can be submitted as well. When choosing card picture, try to avoid copyrighted pictures. Such pictures will be replaced in case the respective copyright holder will request it.</p>

<h4>Card template</h4>

<p>To create new cards in the Concepts section, that are actually implementable, you need to follow certain restrictions. For example a card effect must be done in a single turn. Continuous effects are not supported. A card can only use/effect data described below:</p>

<p>Game data (both player and opponent has their own data with the exception of round)</p>

<ul>
	<li>Tower</li>
	<li>Wall</li>
	<li>Quarry</li>
	<li>Magic</li>
	<li>Dungeon</li>
	<li>Bricks</li>
	<li>Gems</li>
	<li>Recruits</li>
	<li>Round</li>
	<li>Changes done previous round (can be used only at the start of each round, contains data about Tower, Wall Facilities and resources)</li>
	<li>Tokens</li>
	<li>Production factor for each facility (default value is 1, multiplies with keyword side-effects)</li>
</ul>

<p>Card history - cards played during this/previous round</p>
<p>Discarded cards:</p>

<ul>
	<li>dicarded by card effect during last round from player's hand</li>
	<li>dicarded by card effect during last round from opponent's hand</li>
	<li>dicarded by standard discard action</li>
</ul>

<p>Card data</p>

<ul>
	<li>Bricks</li>
	<li>Gems</li>
	<li>Recruits</li>
	<li>Keywords and effect (supports all filter conditions that are in the deck section). Keywords can have one parameter (like Charge), but it cannot be dynamic.</li>
	<li>New card flag (whether the card is new or not)</li>
	<li>Reveal flag (used only in games with hidden cards)</li>
	<li>Tokens</li>
</ul>

<p>Unsupported card effects</p>

<ul>
	<li>continuous card effects (effects that manipulate future turns)</li>
	<li>using card effects of other cards</li>
	<li>card effects based on results of the keyword effects</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Settings">
		<![CDATA[
<p>In this section you may customize MArcomage. Profile settings contain information about player identity, none of them is mandatory. When filled in, all other players are able to see this information. Account settings are used to adjust MArcomage to player's needs. It is possible to change password, set timezone, select skin and game background image. There are some layout options (described below).</p>

<h4>Layout options</h4>

<ul>
	<li>Players list filter - determine default value of the players list filter</li>
	<li>Skin selection - select a skin that will be used throughout the whole site</li>
	<li>Game background - select a game background picture that will be shown in the Game section only</li>
	<li>Auto refresh - activate automatic refresh in the Games section, which is based on the selected value</li>
	<li>Cards per row - specify how many cards will fit into one row of the card pool in the deck editor</li>
	<li>Advanced games list - display Last seen (opponent) and Last game action (game) dates in the Games list section</li>
	<li>Show card images - display card image (turn off on slow internet connection)</li>
	<li>Show keyword insignias - display card keywords in form of an insignia instead of text form</li>
	<li>Hide card pool - card pool will be hidden by default in the deck editor</li>
	<li>Play card buttons - each card in game will have a local play button (if playable) instead of global play button</li>
	<li>Show nationality in players list - display text description of players' nationality in the players list</li>
	<li>Reverse chat message order - reverses chat order in the chatbox (game section). By default chat messages are ordered from newest (top) to oldest (bottom)</li>
	<li>Integrated chat - integrate chat into the game screen instead of using chat pop-up tool</li>
	<li>Show avatar in game - display avatars of both players in the game</li>
	<li>Show avatar in players list - display avatar in players list for all players who have an avatar</li>
	<li>Avatar display correction for chat - used to prevent Firefox 2.x display bug</li>
	<li>Old card appearance - display cards with old appearance</li>
	<li>Mini card flags - display mini card flags (new card and revealed flags) within card picture instead of standard card flags</li>
	<li>Battle report messages - when active, system will automaticaly send private message to inform you about a game outcome (when it finishes) or when someone accepts or rejects your challenge</li>
	<li>Forum notification - display forum notification (new posts) in the menubar</li>
	<li>Concepts notification - display concepts notification (new concepts) in the menubar</li>
	<li>Random deck selection - allow to choose a random deck to play with when starting a game</li>
	<li>Disallow simultaneous games - disallow simultaneous games against the same opponent</li>
</ul>

<h4>Menubar notification</h4>

<p>By default, player is informed about new posts in the forum and new card concepts in the concepts section with small animated images in the upper navigation bar. This can be turned off in the settings section.</p>

<h4>RN button</h4>

<p>Menubar notification can be reset with "Reset notification" button (this will unmark all new posts and messages, it's the same as doing logout-login procedure).</p>

<h4>Avatar</h4>
<p>
In the settings section you can upload your own avatar. Avatar must be a jpg, jpeg, png or gif image type, must have at most 10kB and should be 60px X 60px large. If it isn't, it will be resized to this size. Avatars with inappropriate content will be deleted and could also lead to ban.
</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Statistics">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Statistics section provides various statistical reports:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Most played - Top 10 most played cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is played</li>
	<li>Most discarded - Top 10 most discarded cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is discarded by standard discard or by card effect</li>
	<li>Least played - Top 10 least played cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is played</li>
	<li>Least discarded - Top 10 least discarded cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is discarded by standard discard or by card effect</li>
	<li>Most drawn - Top 10 most drawn cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is drawn by any draw type</li>
	<li>Least drawn - Top 10 least drawn cards, this statistic is updated each time a card is drawn by any draw type</li>
	<li>Skins - for each skin type (layout setting), the usage ratio is shown (how many players use that skin compared to total skins used), only active and offline players contribute to this statistic</li>
	<li>Game modes - the percentage shown is how many games use the respective game mode (compared to all games in total), only finished games contribute to this statistic</li>
	<li>Victory types - for each victory type, the percentage ratio is shown (how many games ended with the respective victory type compared to all games in total), only finished games contribute to this statistic</li>
	<li>Backgrounds - for each background type (layout setting), the usage ratio is shown (how many players use that background compared to total backgrounds used), only active and offline players contribute to this statistic</li>
	<li>Suggested concepts - Top 10 authors of suggested card concepts (only card concepts with status "waiting" and "interesting" are counted)</li>
	<li>Implemented concepts - Top 10 authors of implemented card concepts (only card concepts with status "implemented" are counted)</li>
</ul>

<p>The difference between "lastest" and "overall" statistics is the fact that "lastest" statistics are reset every time new cards are added to provide fair competition between new and old cards. "overall" statistics are never reset, so the older the card, the bigger is the advantage compared to new, younger cards. Default length of card statistics list is 10, but this can be changed via the card list length selector at the top of the statistics page. Usage factor is calculated for each card to compare card usage to other cards of the same rarity.</p>

<h4>Versus statistics</h4>

<p>Versus statistics are available in the player's details section. These statistics show information about games where two players played against each other (first player is the one viewing the player's details section and second player is the one being viewed). Statistics are calculated from the first player perspective. When viewing own profile, player's overall game statistics are shown instead of Versus statistics.</p>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="BB code">
		<![CDATA[
<ul>
	<li>[b]some_text[/b] will add bold font weight to <b>some_text</b></li>
	<li>[i]some_text[/i] will add italic style to <i>some_text</i></li>
	<li>[link]internal_url[/link] will make a hyperlink from the provided internal_url (used to reference pages within MArcomage website)</li>
	<li>[link=internal_url]some text[/link] will make a hyperlink from some text pointing to location described by internal_url (used to reference pages within MArcomage website)</li>
	<li>[url]external_url[/url] will make a hyperlink from the provided external_url (used to reference pages outside MArcomage website)</li>
	<li>[url=external_url]some text[/url] will make a hyperlink from some text pointing to location described by external_url (used to reference pages outside MArcomage website)</li>
	<li>[quote]some_text[/quote] will make a quote containing some_text</li>
	<li>[quote=some_name]some_text[/quote] will make a quote containing some_text with some_name as quote author</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Color information">
		<![CDATA[
<p>Some information is not presented in a text form, but is encoded into text color. Here is a list of the semantics of different text colors you may encounter throughout the game.</p>

<ul>
	<li>In the players section, player name color holds the information about player's activity
		<ul>
			<li><b>Lime</b> (or <b>Green</b>) (online) means that player was active in last 10 minutes. This kind of information can be found in other sections too, for example challenges and games</li>
			<li><b>Red</b> (offline) means that player was active in last 7 days</li>
			<li><b>Dark red</b> (inactive) means that player was active in last 21 days</li>
			<li><b>Gray</b> (dead) means that player was inactive for more than 21 days</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
	<li>In the game section color holds information about player activity. Opponent's name (located above tower and wall info) is in <b>Lime</b> (or <b>Green</b>) color, when he is online</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
	<part name="Keyboard shortcuts">
		<![CDATA[
<p>(might not work in some browsers without re-configuring them)</p>
<ul>
	<li>ALT+s - send chat message</li>
	<li>ALT+a - set focus to chat window</li>
	<li>ALT+w - refresh button</li>
	<li>ALT+q - logout</li>
</ul>
		]]>
	</part>
</help>
