<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- MArcomage tutorial -->
<tutorial xmlns="http://arcomage.netvor.sk">
  <part name="webpage" order="1">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Welcome to MArcomage</h3>
  <p>Greetings player. This tutorial will briefly guide you throughout MArcomage and will explain basic functionality on the way. While in the tutorial mode you may not interact with MArcomage functionality, but you can <b>resize</b> and <b>reposition</b> this dialog to allow you to inspect the content. You may also decide to skip this tutorial by pressing the <b>Skip tutorial</b> button at any time. This tutorial can be restarted by pressing the <b>Restart tutorial</b> button in the <b>Settings</b> section.</p>
    <p>We are now located in the <b>Webpage</b> section. Here you can read about latest MArcomage news such as new features, new cards and latest balance changes.</p>
    <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to the <b>Games</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="games" order="2">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Games section</h3>
  <p>The screen is divided into two parts. The left screen contains list of your <b>active games</b> to allow you to access and play your games. Right now the list of active games is empty, but once you create a new game, the game can be accessed by pressing the <b>&gt;</b> button located in the active games list row.</p>
  <p>The right part of the screen contains <b>games management</b>. With it, you are able to create new games or join games created by other players. AI games (games against computer opponent) are also created here. We will now create a new game for you.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to your newly created game in the <b>Game</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="games_details" order="3">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Game section</h3>
  <p>Each player has exactly <b>eight</b> cards in his or hers hand. Your cards are located at the <b>upper</b> part of the screen. Opponent's cards are located in the <b>bottom</b> part of the screen. On your turn you can <b>play a card</b> by selecting it (clicking on it) and pressing the <b>Play</b> button. Of course, you need to have enough resources to pay for the <b>card cost</b>.</p>
  <p>There are three types of resources: <b>Bricks</b>, <b>Gems</b> and <b>Recruits</b>, and three types of resource production facilities: <b>Quarry</b>, <b>Magic</b> and <b>Dungeon</b>. Bricks are the basic building material, used mostly for constructing buildings. Gems represent the magical power at your disposal. And finally, recruits represent your living or fighting power. At the end of round, for each facility of certain type, one resource of the corresponding type is added to player's stock. Your resources and facilities are located in the <b>center-left</b> part of the screen. Opponent's resources and facilities are located in the <b>center-right</b> part of the screen.</p>
  <p>Every player has <b>tower</b> and <b>wall</b>. Tower height can be at most 100 (150 in long mode), wall has height limit 150 (225 in long mode). In the case of a standard enemy attack, the attack will first lower the wall. Only after the wall height is zero and some attack power still remains will the tower be lowered. There are some cards that do damage the tower directly, bypassing the wall. Tower and wall information are located in the <b>bottom-left</b> part (yours) and <b>bottom-right</b> (opponent's).</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Decks</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="decks" order="4">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Decks section</h3>
  <p>In this section you can see list of your decks and information about them. Each player starts with three pre-built <b>starter decks</b>. In the beginning it's advised to use these decks to play with, but with time you may want to <b>adjust</b> these decks and even <b>create</b> new ones. To inspect a deck click on the <b>&gt;</b> button located in the deck list row. We will inspect one of your starter decks now.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Deck</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="decks_edit" order="5">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Deck section</h3>
  <p><b>Card pool</b> is located in the upper part of the screen. It contains all cards that are available for selection. Below it, your <b>deck</b> is located. To <b>hide</b> the card pool push the <b>Hide card pool</b> button located in the upper-right part of the screen. Once it's hidden, <b>Hide card pool</b> button is changed to <b>Show card pool</b> button which can be used to <b>show</b> the card pool once again. Card pool can be adjusted by using various <b>filters</b> that are located in the upper-left part of the screen.</p>
  <p>To <b>take</b> a card from card pool to your deck, simply click on it. You can <b>remove</b> a card from your deck by clicking on it in your deck.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Deck</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="messages" order="6">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Messages section</h3>
  <p>Challenges and private messages that you received are located here. If you accept a <b>challenge</b> from another player a game will be created. Private <b>messages</b> are used as an alternative way to communicate with other players when in-game chat is not available.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Players</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="players" order="7">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Players section</h3>
  <p>This section contains list of all <b>players</b> and their <b>profiles</b>. <b>Filters</b> that are located in the upper-center part of the screen can be used to search for specific players that match only the selected filter criteria.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Replays</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="replays" order="8">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Replays section</h3>
  <p>All games are recorded and stored for players to watch later. Here, you can review your games to improve your skills or watch games of other players to learn from their tactics. <b>Filters</b> that are located in the upper-center part of the screen can be used to search for specific game replays.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Forum</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="forum" order="9">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Forum section</h3>
  <p>MArcomage has it's own <b>discussion forum</b>. If you have any questions regarding MArcomage, ask other players in the <b>General</b> section of the forum. If you encounter problems with MArcomage, you can report the issues in the <b>Support</b> section of our forum.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Cards</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="cards" order="10">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Cards section</h3>
  <p>MArcomage entire card database can be viewed here. <b>Filters</b> located in the upper-center part of the screen can be used to find specific cards.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Card concepts</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="concepts" order="11">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Card concepts section</h3>
  <p>All players can create new cards and submit them for implementation. Also, card concepts of other players can be viewed here as well.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Next</b> button to continue to <b>Settings</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
  <part name="settings" order="12">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>Settings section</h3>
  <p>In this section you can <b>customize</b> MArcomage. <b>Profile settings</b> contain information about your <b>identity</b>, none of them is mandatory. When filled in, all other players are able to see this information. <b>Account settings</b> are used to <b>adjust</b> MArcomage to your best liking. Additionally, MArcomage <b>shop</b> is located here, right below the profile settings. In the shop you can buy additional features such as bonus game and deck slots.</p>
  <p>This concludes our tutorial. Please see the <b>Game manual</b> (<b>Help</b> section) for more detailed information about MArcomage.</p>
  <p>Once you're ready click on the <b>Finish tutorial</b> button to end the tutorial. This tutorial can be restarted by pressing the <b>Restart tutorial</b> button in the <b>Settings</b> section.</p>
  ]]>
  </part>
</tutorial>
